<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.hjosugi.WaylandFeatherShot</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>

  <name>Feather Shot</name>
  <summary>Wayland-first screenshot tool with annotation and scrolling capture</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ja">Wayland専用スクリーンショット(注釈・スクロールキャプチャ対応)</summary>

  <description>
    <p>
      Flameshot-style screenshot tool built Wayland-first. Freeze the screen,
      drag a selection, and annotate it in place with a floating toolbar —
      pen, line, arrow, rectangle, ellipse, highlighter, text, blur, pixelate,
      auto-numbered markers and crop. Save to disk or copy to the clipboard.
    </p>
    <p>
      It also records a scrolling capture while you scroll and stitches the
      frames into one tall image.
    </p>
    <p>
      100% local: no upload button, no accounts, no telemetry, and no network
      code at all. Every capture goes through xdg-desktop-portal, so it works
      on GNOME, KDE Plasma, Hyprland, Sway and anything with a portal backend.
    </p>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.hjosugi.WaylandFeatherShot.desktop</launchable>

  <categories>
    <category>Graphics</category>
    <category>Utility</category>
  </categories>

  <keywords>
    <keyword>screenshot</keyword>
    <keyword>capture</keyword>
    <keyword>annotate</keyword>
    <keyword>blur</keyword>
    <keyword>scroll</keyword>
    <keyword>wayland</keyword>
  </keywords>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/hjosugi/wayland-feather-shot</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/hjosugi/wayland-feather-shot/issues</url>

  <provides>
    <binary>wayland-feather-shot</binary>
  </provides>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>

  <releases>
    <release version="0.7.9" date="2026-07-09">
      <description>
        <p>
          Follow-up release for the updater remove command that keeps the
          GitHub release workflow green when optional AUR publishing cannot
          authenticate.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.8" date="2026-07-09">
      <description>
        <p>
          Adds a GTK-free updater remove command for uninstalling files managed
          by install.sh while keeping user configuration, and extends the
          release tooling with optional AUR publishing support.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.7" date="2026-07-08">
      <description>
        <p>
          Makes optional RemoteDesktop-portal auto-scroll discoverable from the
          scrolling-capture window, gates it on actual portal availability,
          adds diagnostics and tests for the stop policy, and documents
          per-desktop behavior while keeping manual scrolling the default.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.6" date="2026-07-08">
      <description>
        <p>
          Makes the region-overlay annotation toolbar theme-independent so the
          tool buttons stay high-contrast and readable — previously their labels
          rendered white-on-white and the buttons collapsed into ovals under
          dark or third-party GTK themes — and restores the blue active-tool
          highlight.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.5" date="2026-07-08">
      <description>
        <p>
          Improves light/dark theme handling by syncing GTK with the desktop
          portal appearance setting, strengthening custom overlay contrast and
          reducing the region-selection dim layer for better readability.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.4" date="2026-07-06">
      <description>
        <p>
          Completes release packaging: automated AppImage, wheel, sdist, AUR
          bundle and checksum generation, plus corrected AUR version metadata.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.3" date="2026-07-06">
      <description>
        <p>
          Adds an open-save-folder action to the screenshot UI, fixes source
          launches when PATH points to a non-distro Python without GTK
          bindings, and cleans up GI version warnings found during a real
          GNOME Wayland validation pass.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.2" date="2026-07-06">
      <description>
        <p>Release hygiene: default shortcut wording, settings test
        file-handle cleanup, and refreshed headless validation.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.1" date="2026-07-06">
      <description>
        <p>Bug fixes: auto-scroll fallback message, and a capture-window
        close-button hang; added CI.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.0" date="2026-07-06">
      <description>
        <p>
          Editor and capture goodies: step-arrow/speech-bubble/emoji
          annotations, colour presets, WebP/AVIF export, local OCR/QR,
          a recent-screenshots gallery, a settings window, and GIF recording.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.6.0" date="2026-07-06">
      <description>
        <p>
          First cuts of multi-monitor edge snapping, fractional-scaling hairline
          alignment, and optional RemoteDesktop-portal auto-scroll.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.5.0" date="2026-07-06">
      <description>
        <p>
          Scrolling capture now works without GStreamer via a manual
          repeated-screenshot fallback that feeds the same stitcher.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.4.0" date="2026-07-06">
      <description>
        <p>
          Reliable Ctrl+PrtSc global shortcut with desktop-aware setup and
          diagnostics, a window-capture mode via the portal picker, and a
          gettext localization backend for adding languages.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.0" date="2026-07-06">
      <description>
        <p>
          Editor gains a select tool (move/delete/restyle shapes), multi-line
          text with outline, flatten-and-blur, and pin-to-screen. Scriptable
          capture flags, faster and more robust scroll stitching, a bundled
          clipboard holder, and packaging.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.0" date="2026-07-05">
      <description>
        <p>
          Unified app: added edit and diagnose modes and reverse-DNS app id.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.0" date="2026-07-05">
      <description>
        <p>First release.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
